

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · SOFTWARE ARCHITECTURE RESEARCHER · SOFTWARE REPOSITORY MINER

941 Bloom Walk, Los Angeles, CA 90089-0781, U.S.

□ (+1) 213-884-8846 | ■ ducmle@usc.edu | ★ lemduc.info | □ lemduc | 🖬 lemduc |

# **Summary**\_

Blends research experience in Software Engineering and Data Mining with diverse and practical trainings in the software industries of Vietnam, S.Korea and U.S. to offer solid skills in software design and development. Experiences include (1) mining software repositories/big data, (2) developing cloudbased applications and web services, (3) architecture design, recovery, and analysis, (4) software product line engineering.

Los Angeles, U.S.

Pohana, S.Korea

Hanoi, Vietnam

Seattle, WA, USA

Aug. 2010 - May. 2012

Aug. 2013 - May. 2018 (Expected)

### **Education**

### **University of Southern California (USC)**

PhD in Computer Science, Software Architecture Research Group (SoftArch), GPA: 3.87/4.00

### Pohang University of Science and Technology (POSTECH)

MSc in Information Technology Convergence Engineering, Software Engineering Lab (SELab), GPA: 95.9/100.0

### Hanoi University of Science and Technology (HUST)

#### BSc in Information Technology (Magna Cum Laude), GPA: 8.07/10.00 Aug. 2005 - May. 2010

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Bloomberg L.P. New York, New York, U.S.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER June. 2018 - PRESENT

**NEC Laboratories America, Inc.** Princeton, New Jersey, U.S. RESEARCH INTERN - COMPUTER SECURITY GROUP May. 2017 - Aug. 2017

**Veritas Technologies LLC** Culver, California, U.S.

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN - EV.CLOUD PROJECT, PLATFORM TEAM May. 2016 - Aug. 2016

**Samsung Research America** Irvine, California, U.S.

RESEARCH INTERN - ADVANCED PRINTING SOFTWARE LAB Jun. 2015 - Sep. 2015

**Dasan Handysoft** Seoul, S.Korea SOFTWARE ENGINEER Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013

**HDC Media Vietnam** Hanoi, Vietnam

PHP DEVELOPER & ASTERISK PBX ADMINISTRATOR Aug. 2009 - Jun. 2010

# Skills

2018

**Programming** Java (Proficient), Python, Linux Shell, PHP, JavaScript, C/C++ **Frameworks** Spark, Spring, OSGi, EMF, GWT, Joomla, Liferay, Microsoft Azure

Databases MySQL, MongoDB

Others Agile Development, LTFX, SVN, Git, Asterisk PBX

### Relevant Coursework

Best Paper Award, ICSA 2018

Software Engineering	Advanced Algorithms	Machine Learning	Database Systems
Software Architecture	Artificial Intelligence	Natural Language Processing	Information and Data Modeling
Software Testing	Decision Support Systems	Advanced Operating Systems	Information Security

# Honors & Awards

2016	'Thesis in Three' - Best Presentation Award, Doctoral Symposium, ICSE 2016	Austin, TX, USA
2015	Awardee, ACM SigSoft CAPS Travel Support for attending ICSE 2015	Florence, Italy
2014	Awardee, USC Doctoral Student Summer Institute Award	Los Angeles, CA, U.S.
2013	Awardee, Vietnam Education Foundation Fellowship	U.S.
2011	Best Poster Prize, 3rd International Symposium on IT Convergence Engineering	Pohang, S.Korea
2010	Awardee, Research Scholarship from National Research Foundation of Korea	Pohang, S. Korea
2010	Awardee, Certificate of Merit for Excellent Graduation Achievement	Hanoi, Vietnam